Adam Watters

Front End Engineer

<u>adamwatters11@gmail.com</u> • <u>adamwatters.nyc</u> • <u>github.com/adamwatters</u>

SUMMARY

Creative engineer with deep experience writing code for the web. Full stack contributor across legacy and greenfield projects at a startup. Lead a team of five developers frontend developers at a digital agency. Open source contributor and constant learner.

EXPERIENCE

Ideawork Studios - Lead Frontend Developer

FEB 2017 - APR 2018

- Led a team of five in the pixel perfect implementation of web designs
- Built tools and established processes to increase development speed and quality
- Maintained and improved a Node CMS with a React/Redux UI

TheLadders.com - Frontend Engineer

DEC 2014 - DEC 2015

- Built out TheLadders.com, landing pages, engineering blog
- Created SEO optimized job search results pages
- Used React to build tools for creating and reviewing resumes

Highlighted Projects

2016 - PRESENT

- Color Pick creator the only VSCode color picker extension that works everywhere and has no dependencies
- Woodblock Print Search personal project Algolia and Gatsby powered website for exploring the Metropolitan Museum's collection of Japanese art
- Netlify Menubar contributed code Electron app for interacting with the Netlify API from MacOS menubar
- Netlify CMS contributed documentation React app for using git as a content backend
- Alice, myalice.com freelance used React/Redux to build a business facing dashboard
- <u>Technical assistant to mentalist</u> freelance used React and Express to build a convincing replica of the iOS contacts app in the browser
- Heartwood School Library Catalog personal project used Ruby on Rails to build a catalog for the library at the Heartwood School of Homebuilding Crafts

EDUCATION

The Recurse Center ("a self-directed learning retreat for programmers")

SEPT 2014 - NOV 2014

- Collaborated and pair programmed within a community of engineers, mathematicians, artists, and data scientists
- Presented on the technical details of web development projects and tools
- Implemented algorithms and data structures

Bucknell University - BA in Economics

SEPT 2007 - MAY 2011

TECH

Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, Jest, React Native, Electron, CSS/SCSS, Gulp/Grunt/Webpack Node, Express, Ruby-on-Rails, SQL, NoSQL, REST APIs, GraphQL Git, Continuous Integration, AWS, Digital Ocean, Unix-like Operating Systems, BASH